SUHAIB KIANI

email: suhaibkiani@gmail.com; phone: 917 432 8410; webpage: https://suhaib471.github.io/

SUMMARY

Core Competencies

- Data Analysis & Visualization
- Business Intelligence
- Project Management
- Financial Modeling & Valuation
- Private Equity & Venture Capital
- Business Strategy & Fundraising
- Data Science & Statistics
- Predictive Modeling & Forecasting
- Machine Learning & Automation

Profile Overview

Seasoned data and investment professional with a broad combination of technical skills (Columbia data certification and LSE MSc Finance degree), domain knowledge (across several industries and geographies) and project management experience (refined ability to manage teams, build relationships, and drive collective actions to produce results).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Concordia Data Sciences New York

Freelance - Data Science & Data Management Consultant

Jan 2019- Present

Working on predictive modeling, data analytics and visualizations for Draper Oakwood and select start-up projects. Key projects include: Mertium.com (developed IBM Watson based NLP model for aggregating news headlines); Innonation.pk (healthcare, digital development solutions for Covid-19 predictive analysis and contact tracing); Reebonz (optimizing recommendation engine for online retail customer base of over 6 million members).

Draper Oakwood Technology Acquisition, Inc.

New York

Data Analysis & Valuation Lead

Sept 2017- Jan 2019

Responsible for data analysis, modeling and due diligence for private equity fund led by Tim Draper, investing in technology companies with data centric focus across US, Chinese and Asian markets. Completed NASDAQ listing for Reebonz, a leading online retail platform for luxury products in the Asia Pacific region.

Indus Basin Holding

Mauritius | Islamabad

Vice President - Business Intelligence

Aug 2009 – June 2017

Managed data analytics, financial evaluation, and business plan implementation for tech focused venture cap firm with social impact investments in agri-tech and energy sectors across South Asia. Pioneered and managed contract farming database model of smallholder farmers for Mars Foods (basmati rice) and oil companies (guar beans).

Bank of America - Merrill Lynch / KASB Securities

London | Islamabad | Karachi

Senior Associate, EMEA Investment Banking (Energy & Power)

Sep 2001–April 2009

Overall origination and execution advisory transactions across the Europe, Middle East and North Africa regions. Lead managed large privatization projects for national oil companies in Pakistan with data resource centers and probabilistic modeling of 75+ oil and gas fields. Successful projects with a collective value of over \$8.0bn.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Columbia University

New York

Data Science Certification (School of Engineering & Applied Science)

Oct 2019 – Mar 2020

London School of Economics & Political Science

London

Master of Science, Finance & Accounting

Sep 1998 – Jul 1999

University of London

London | Lahore

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Finance & Accounting

Sep 1994 – Jul 1997

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office suite, Python, SQL, Tableau, Looker, D3, Pandas, Matpotlib, JavaScript, PowerPoint, CSS.

INTERESTS

North Indian classical music; Off-road Motorsports; Mixed Martial Arts and Photography.